もういっちょう！
One more!
ニヒヒ！ ん？ 今　右手　使ったでしょ。
You just used your right hand!
くぁ！　やった！
I did it!
ひゃっほ！
Hooray...
夜が明けて ゴン達を乗せた飛行船は
Dawn breaks, as the airship carrying Gon and his friends
目的地へと差しかかる
approaches its destination.
第３次ハンター試験の 幕開けである
The Third Phase of the Hunter Exam
is about to begin.
お待たせいたしました。
I apologize for the long wait.
この飛行船は　間もなく 目的地に到着いたします。
The airship will soon arrive
at its destination.
うわぁ！
Wow!
あれが次の試験会場か！
Is that where the next test will be held?
何だ　ここは… 何もないぞ？
What is this place? There's nothing here.
あ。
Ahem...
皆様　３次試験の スタート地点は　ここ 「トリックタワー」と呼ばれる塔の てっぺんとなります。
Everyone, the exam's Third Phase
will begin here, at the top of Trick Tower.
トリックタワー？
Trick Tower?
合格の条件は　この塔を 生きて下まで下りて来ること。
To pass this phase, you must reach the tower's base alive.
制限時間は　７２時間です。
The time limit is seventy-two hours.
それでは　これより ３次試験を開始いたします。
With that, we will now begin
the Third Phase.
皆様の健闘をお祈りします。 ウソだろ？　おい。
I will pray for your success. No way.
そろそろ出番か…。
So it's finally my turn?
皆さん 頑張ってくださいね。
Best of luck to everyone!
うわぁ。 まさか　ここを下りろってのか？
Are we supposed to climb down?
自殺行為に等しいな。
That would be suicide...
フフっ　普通の人間ならな
Maybe for a normal person.
これくらい 一流のロッククライマーなら 難なくクリアできるぜ。
But a top-class rock climber can
handle this, no problem.
すっげぇ。 どんどん下りてく…。
Wow... He's going down pretty fast.
フフン！　どうやら３次試験の 合格第１号は 俺様のようだな…　ん？
Looks like I'll be the first one
to pass the Third Phase...
やめろ…　来るなぁ！
Stop! Stay away!
やめろ！　やめてくれ！ うわぁ!!
Stop! Stop it!
助けてくれ…！
Help!
壁を使って下りるのは 無理みてぇだな…。
G-Guess we can't climb down the side...
ああ…。
Yeah.
お…　どうした？
What's up?
人数が減っている…。 何!?
There are fewer people around. What?
全部で２３人…。 半数近くが　すでに　ここから 脱出したことになる。
I count twenty-three, which suggests almost half of the
applicants have already found an exit.
ウソだろ　いつの間に…。
No way. When did they do that?
この屋上の　どこかに
That means there must be
下に通じる隠し扉があることは 間違いないんだが…。
some hidden doors that lead below.
クラピカ！ レオリオ！
Kurapika! Leorio!
どうした？　ゴン。
What is it, Gon?
これ　隠し扉を見つけたんだ。
Look. I found a hidden door.
おぉ！
I see now.
なるほど　石畳が回転することで 下へ下りられる仕組みか。
So we can descend by flipping the stones.
よっしゃ！　でかした　ゴン！
Okay! Great job, Gon!
早速　下へ下りようぜ。
Let's head on down!
でも　迷ってるんだ。 何を迷うことがあんだよ。
But I'm confused. About what?
ここと　そこと　あそこと あそこにもあるんだ　隠し扉。
There are also hidden doors here,
there, over there, and over there, as well.
そんなに？
That many?
密集する５つの隠し扉か いかにも　うさんくさいな。
Five hidden doors,
located in the same area. It sounds suspicious to me.
いくつかは罠かもしれない…。
Some could be traps.
しかも　この扉　たった１回しか 使えないみたいなんだよな。
And it looks as though each door can only be used once...
マジで？
Seriously?
もう一度　開けてみようと 思ったんだけど びくともしなかった。
We tried opening a door
someone else used, but it wouldn't budge.
扉の幅からして　下りられるのは １回につき　１人だけ…。
Judging by the door's size, only one can fit at a time.
つまり　扉は１人につき　１つずつ。
In other words, only one person
can use each door.
みんなバラバラの道を行かなきゃ いけないってこと。
We'll have to split up.
ゴンと俺は　この中から１つずつ 選ぶことに決めた。
Gon and I decided that we're each
going to choose a door.
罠にかかっても恨みっこなし！
No hard feelings if one
of us springs a trap!
レオリオとクラピカは　どうする？
What are you guys gonna do?
いいだろう 「運も実力のうち」ってな。
I can live with that. Luck is part of the game...
私も異論はない　決まったな。
I have no objection. Then that settles it.
イチ　ニのサンで 全員一緒に行こうぜ。
Let's go, on the count of three.
みんなとは ここで　いったん　お別れだね。
I guess this is goodbye for now.
地上で再び会おう。
We'll meet up again, at the tower's base.
じゃあ行くぜ…　イチ！
Let's go... One!
ニの…！
Two!
サン！
Three!
えっ？
Huh?
あっ…。 えっ…　あれ!?
Huh? What?
エッヘヘヘ…。 ハハ…。 短い別れだったな。
That was quite a brief farewell.
何だよ　どれを選んでも 結局　同じ部屋に下りるように なってやがったのかよ…。
Oh, so all the doors led to the same room...
「君達５人は　ここから ゴールまでの道のりを
"The five of you
多数決で乗り越えなければ ならない」だってさ。
must follow the will of the majority
to reach the goal."
５人？ 見て　タイマーも５人分あるよ。
Five of us? Look... There are five stopwatches.
「○」と「×」のボタンが ついてるな。
There's an O and an X button.
もしかして…　あと１人 誰か　この部屋に下りて来るまで
Could it be that we won't be
able to leave this room
我々は　ここから 出られないのではないか？
until another person drops in?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　その通り！ 誰だ!?
That is correct! Who's that?!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　私の名はリッポー。
My name is Lippo.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　刑務所所長　兼 第３次試験の試験官だ。
I am the prison warden here, as well as the Third Phase examiner.
刑務所所長？
Prison warden?
このタワーには 幾通りものルートが用意されている。
Multiple routes through this tower
have been prepared.
お前達が選んだのは　多数決の道。
You have chosen the path
of majority rule.
クリアのためには　互いの協力が 必要絶対条件となる。
Cooperation will be key if you wish to clear this
phase of the exam.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　たった１人のわがままは 決して通らない　難コースだ。
One person's selfish behavior
can derail an entire group.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　そして　このコースは ５人揃わなければ始められない。
And you can't start until you
have five members.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　では　諸君らの健闘を祈る。
Best of luck, gentlemen!
はぁ…　あと１人　来なきゃ 前に進めねえってよぉ。
We can't move on until
someone else arrives?
どうすんだよ？
What do we do?
待つしかない…　か。
We have to wait, I guess...
テストを開始する 各自　配置に就け。
The test begins now. Take your assigned positions.
うぃっす。
Okay.
あぁ！　もう。
Oh, come on!
あれから２時間だぞ！
It's been two hours...
もしかして　もう全員 別のルートから 行っちまったんじゃねえのか!?
What if the others all took
different routes?
今頃　上に残ってんのは よっぽどのマヌケだぜ。
Only a fool would still be at
the top of the tower!
落ち着け　レオリオ 嘆いても始まらん。
Calm down, Leorio. Complaining won't help.
でもよ　このまま誰も来ないで ７２時間経っちまったら どうすんだよ！
But... What if no one shows up before
we reach our time limit? Hey!
何もしねえで…。 シッ　静かに！
I can't just sit here and... Quiet!
あぁ!? 音がする。 あっ！
Huh? That sound...
うぅ…　やれやれ。
Good grief...
トンパさん！
Tonpa-san.
なんだ。 おっさんかよ…。
Oh. It's the old man.
よっしゃ！
Okay!
なるほど　５人揃って タイマーをはめると
I see. So the door appears
ドアが現れる仕掛けか。
once five people arrive and
put on the stopwatches.
「このドアを 『○』開ける　『×』開けない」。
"At this door, select
O to open, X not to open."
もう　ここから多数決か。
Forcing us to use majority rule already?
そんなもん 答えは決まってんのにな。
The answer should be obvious...
あっ！
What?
誰だ？ 「×」のボタンを押したのは。
Who pushed the X button?
ハハハ…　すまん　すまん　俺だ！
Sorry, that was me.
間違って押しちまった。
I pressed the wrong button
by mistake.
ふざけんじゃねえよ！　おっさん あんた　目がイカれてんのか!?
Stop screwing around, old man! Are you blind?
だから　間違えただけだって…。
Like I said, it was an accident.
どうやったら「○」と「×」を 間違えるってんだ！　あぁ!?
How can you accidentally press
the wrong button?!
いいじゃない ドアは　ちゃんと開いたんだし。
It doesn't matter. The door opened.
いいや　よくねえ！
No, it does matter!
こいつ絶対　わざと「×」を 押しやがったんだぜ！
This guy deliberately pressed
the wrong button...
行こう　争っている時間が惜しい。
Let's go. We don't have time to bicker.
そうそう　仮に　そいつが わざと　全部　逆らってもさ 俺達が　まとまってりゃあ いいわけだろ？
That's right... Even if he keeps pressing
the wrong one, the rest of us just need to
press the right one.
うぅ…　分かったよ。
Fine.
ヘヘ…　よっしゃ　行くぜ！
Okay, let's go!
クッ…！
Damn...
おいおい　扉を出て またすぐ設問かよ。
Seriously... Another question so soon?
「どっちに行く？　『○』右　『×』左」。
"Which way do you want to go? O for right. X for left."
右か…
Right...
左か…。
Or left...
はぁ!?
Huh?!
何で右なんだよ こういう時は左だろ？　普通！
Wh-Why would you choose to go right? Normally, you should go left...
確かに　行動学の見地からも 人は迷ったり 分かれ道を選ぶ時には
That is true. Studies have indicated that people
who are lost or stuck at forks
無意識に左を選択するケースが 多いらしい。
unconsciously tend to go left.
それ　俺も聞いたことある。
I've heard that before, too.
ちょっと待て！ それじゃ計算が合わねえぞ！
Wait! The numbers don't add up!
お前ら　一体 どっちを押したんだよ！
Which button did you press?
右。 右。
Right. Right.
お前らなぁ…。
Y-You guys...
だからこそ　右なんだよ 試験官の裏をかくならなぁ。
That's why they chose to go right... To outfox the examiner.
試験官が　左の法則を知っていれば 左の道を難しくするだろ？
If the examiner knows that
people tend to go left, the left path will be more difficult.
ケッ！　どうせ俺達は単純だよ！
So we're just simple-minded!
「俺達」？
We?
何だよ　ここ…。
Wh-What is this place?
見ろよ　あそこ。
Look over there.
受験者が来たぜ 手錠を外してくれ。
The applicants have arrived. Remove the shackles.
やれやれ…。
Jeez...
ようやく解放されたぜ。
I'm finally free.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　諸君　説明しよう。
Allow me to explain, gentlemen.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　諸君らの前にいるのは このトリックタワーに 幽閉されている囚人達だ。
Before you are some of
Trick Tower's prisoners.
囚人？
Prisoners?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　彼らは同時に　審査委員会から 正式に任命を受けた
The Hunter Exam Committee
雇われ試験官でもある。
has also officially hired them
as examiners.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　諸君には　これから　ここで 彼ら５人と戦ってもらう。
You will be fighting against
the five of them.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　勝負は１対１ 各自　一度しか戦えない。
The fights will be one-on-one. Each person may only fight once.
戦い方は自由　引き分けは　なし。
You are free to use any method you like. There will be no draws.
相手に負けを認めさせたら 勝ちとする。
A win is declared when the
opponent admits defeat.
順番は自由に決めてもらって結構。
You may pick your order.
諸君らは多数決
It's majority rule.
つまり　３勝以上すれば ここを通過できる。
So secure three wins, and you may pass.
ルールは極めて単純だ。
The rules are simple.
チッ　ここでも多数決かよ。
Tsk... Majority rule again?
まっ　分かりやすくていいけど。
Well, I prefer straightforward rules.
フッ　しかし 勝負自体は　そう単純ではない。
However, the actual fights will
not be quite so simple.
諸君を足止めした分だけ 刑期が短くなる契約をしている。
The prisoners' sentences will be reduced by one year, for every hour they
delay the applicants here.
つまり　時間稼ぎも 彼らの狙いとなるのだ。
In other words, their goal
is also to buy time.
なるほど…。
I understand...
我々にも　７２時間以内に ゴールしなければならないという 制約がある。
And we must reach the goal
within seventy-two hours.
この勝負　時間の駆け引きも 重要となるわけだな…。
So time will be critical during these fights.
さぁ　こちらの１番手は俺だ そちらも選ばれよ！
Okay, I'm up first. Choose your combatant!
どうする？ 戦い方が自由ってことは
What should we do? He said that we can fight
with any method.
裏を返せば 何でもありってことだぜ？
So that means anything goes.
何を仕掛けて来るか 分からねえってことか…。
We don't know what they'll try to pull...
相手の出方が測れない分 初戦は　リスクが大きい。
There's too much at stake without knowing what they have up their sleeves.
ここは　私が…。
Given that, I shall...
いや　俺が行こう！
No, I'll go!
トンパさん!?
Tonpa-san?
毒味役として 俺が相手の出方をうかがおう。
I'll act as a guinea pig, so we can discover what they're up to.
さっきの詫びも兼ねてな。
Consider this an apology for before.
お前…　本気か？
Hey, are you serious?
ああ　それに　お前さん達は 俺を　いまひとつ 信用しきれてないだろ？
Sure. Plus, you guys don't actually
trust me, right?
そんな俺に　２勝２敗の場面で 登場するような大将役を 任せられるか？
Do you really want me to be the tiebreaker,
when the score is 2-2?
そりゃまぁ　そうだが…。
You have a point...
じゃあ　決まりだな。
Then it's settled.
トンパ…　お前…。 フンっ。
Tonpa, you're...
意外だったな まさか　あのトンパが…。
Th-That was a surprise... I didn't expect Tonpa to volunteer.
自分から毒味役を 言い出すとはな…。
He called himself a guinea pig.
大丈夫かな　トンパさん。
Will Tonpa-san be okay?
さて　勝負の方法を決めようか。
Now, let us determine the
method of combat.
俺は　デスマッチを提案する。
I propose a death match.
おっ。 デスマッチ？
A death match?
死ぬまで戦うってことかよ。
They fight until one dies?
ダメだ 奴の挑発に乗っては　いけない。
No... Don't let him provoke you!
どうする？
Well?
いいだろう　その勝負　受けた！
Very well... I accept!
えっ！ マジかよ。
Huh? Seriously?
その覚悟　見事！
I commend you for your courage!
トンパ…。
T-Tonpa...
いざ…　勝負！
Let the fight begin!
ま　参ったぁ！
I... I give!
はぁ？ 何？
Huh? What?
もしかして 「参った」っていったの？
Did he just give up?
「待った」の間違いじゃないのか？
M-Maybe he meant "Give me a sec"?
今　何と？
What did you just say?
俺が負けを認めれば そっちの勝ちだろ？
You win if I admit defeat, right?
参った　俺の負けだ　ハハハ…。
I give up... I lose!
な…　な…　な…。
Wha... Wha... Wha...
いいだろう　この勝負　俺の勝ちだ。
All right... I win this round.
我々が　あと２勝すれば お前達の負けだ。
If we win two more rounds, you lose.
先に進めず 引き返すこともできず
You won't be able to advance or turn back.
時間切れまで７２時間 ここで　立ち尽くすことになる。
You'll be stuck here until the
seventy-two hours are up.
そうなれば　我々は全員 ７２年分の刑期が短縮されるのだ。 ハハハ…　ハッハッハ…。
Should that come to pass, our sentences will be reduced
by seventy-two years.
いや　面目ない　近くで見ると 強そうなんだもんなぁ。
Man, that was a disgrace. He looked a lot stronger up close...
てめぇ… 今　はっきり分かったぜ！
Bastard... You just confirmed all my suspicions!
てめぇが他人の足を 引っ張ってばかりの クズ野郎だってことをなぁ！
You're a worthless piece of trash, who's only good for sabotaging
other applicants!
その通りさ 俺は　ずっと　そうして来た。
Exactly. That's what I do every year.
そして　これからも そうするつもりさ。
And I plan to continue the tradition.
何？
Wh-What?
俺がハンター試験に 求めているのは　合格じゃ　ない。
I'm not looking to pass the Hunter Exam.
程よい刺激さ。
I'm only in it for the thrills.
刺激？ そうだ。
The thrills? Yes.
食い潰されて行く修羅の場
The Hunter Exam is a trial meant to crush confident young people's dreams.
野心や希望が永遠に断たれる 一瞬の表情 次第に　それを見るのが 何よりの楽しみとなった。
The moment of despair,
when ambition and hope give way, gives me a sense of exquisite pleasure.
俺自身が積極的に加担して 新人の夢を摘み取った。
Especially when I'm actively
shattering these rookies' dreams.
俺は　ハンターになる気なんか はなからないのさ。
I don't plan on becoming a Hunter.
今年は　もう十分に楽しんだ。
I've already had enough fun this year.
俺にしてみれば ここらへんが潮時なんだ。
It's time for me to bow out.
てめぇ！ よせ！　レオリオ！
You bastard... Stop, Leorio!
だが…！
But...
内輪もめで時間を潰すなど 奴らの思うつぼだ。
They want us to waste our time,
fighting amongst ourselves.
でもさ　時間稼ぎも 奴らの狙いだとしたら おっちゃんの選択は 正解だったかもね。
However, if their goal is to buy time, then the old man made
the correct choice.
えっ？
Huh?
あの坊ず頭 恐らく　元軍人か傭兵だよ。
That bald guy is probably a former soldier or mercenary.
戦ってたら まず最初に喉を潰されて 「参った」って いえないようにされてたね。
Had you fought him, he would have started by
crushing your throat, so you couldn't have given up.
あとは死なない程度に 拷問されてたよ 残り時間　ずっと。
Then he would have tortured you,
without killing you, for the rest of the remaining time...
もちろん　それも計算済みよ。
Th-That was one of the possibilities
I took into consideration...
顔色悪ぃぞ。
You look sick.
少々　予定が狂ったな…。
My plan was disrupted.
じわりじわりと　時間をかけて いたぶるつもりだったのだが…。
I was going to take my time,
punishing him...
大丈夫だよ　問題ない。
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
残りの４人が２勝すれば こっちの勝ちなんだから。
If we defeat two of the remaining four, then we win.
ともかく　我々は３勝して 前に進むしか　道はないんだ。
Regardless, we need to win
three rounds and advance.
次は　誰が行く？
Who's going next?
はい！　俺が行くよ！
Me! I'll go!
大丈夫か？ うん！
Are you sure? Uh-huh!
どうやら次の奴は 肉体派じゃなさそうだな。
The next opponent doesn't
look too strong.
だからって　油断は　するなよ。
But you can't let your guard down.
あいつだって　れっきとした 犯罪者なんだからな。
He's still a criminal.
うん　分かってる。
Uh-huh, I know.
トンパの思惑により
Tonpa's actions
不利な状況へと追い込まれた ゴン達
have placed Gon and his friends
at a disadvantage.
次の対戦相手　セドカンとの 勝負に待ち受けているものは 一体　何か？
What is their next opponent, Sedokan, planning to do in this match?
第３次ハンター試験に ４０名が参加し
At the start of the Hunter Exam's Third Phase, there were 40 applicants.
すでに１名が脱落 残り３９名
With 1 eliminated, only 39 remain.